MIQUEL SUAU GONZÀLEZ

Barcelona, Spain · +34 611 48 22 45 · sq.miquel@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/miquel-suau-gonzalez

GitHub: https://github.com/MayKoder Portfolio: https://maykoder.github.io/maykoder/

Hi! My name is Miquel, and I'm a software and video game developer from Barcelona. I'm actively trying to expand my knowledge through practical experience while using it to create exciting experiences and helpful software.

I also have been teaching the "Game Engines" class at UPC School, which further developed my soft skills as a lecturer. Despite my fluency with C++, I have expertise not just with a variety of languages, but also with multiple frameworks and API.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UPC School (Polytechnic University of Catalonia), Terrassa, Barcelona

2022 - Present

College Lecturer

• Lecturer for the "Creation and Development of Videogames" CITM Official Degree. In charge of the "Game Engines" 2022–2023 course, which requires students to build a game engine from scratch using C++ and OpenGL.

Zitro Laboratory, Sant Quirze del Vallès, Barcelona

2022 – Present

Junior C++ Developer

• My primary responsibility as a C++ developer was to correct and optimize the rendering engine and add functionality to it while adhering to the established coding standards. I participated in the entire 6-month creation of a new product that was introduced in Brazil.

The Brain Therapy, Barcelona, Spain

2021 - 2022

Intern to Junior Software Developer

• Started as an intern for the startup and developed with my boss' supervision the main app and all the frontend (all screens and interactions with the app) and backend code. Developed a Python firebase manager for non-programmers management. Currently, a Junior dev.

Valking, Barcelona, Spain

2021-2022

Mobile Application Developer

• Developed 3 apps with flutter with another teammate. Dealt with front and back end and programmed the database code. The apps were an automatic upgrade and two production ready apps for subscriptions and video streaming.

Lateral Thinking Code, Terrassa, Spain

2019-2019

Programming Tutor

• Worked during the summer break as a coding teacher with various languages and platforms with 10-16 year old kids. Achieved a teacher grade of average 96% of student satisfaction.

EDUCATION

Image Processing and Multimedia Technology Center, Terrassa, Spain

2018-2022

Bachelor's degrees in Video Game Design and Development

- Awards: Honors grade PROGIVJ (only 2 awarded to class), Best game engine (Only 1 awarded in class)
- Completed one-semester study abroad with Glasgow Caledonian University

TOP ACHIEVEMENTS

Diamond Engine Jun 2021

• Engine developed in 4 months from scratch. Has MonoRuntime and C# linking and shader scripting. Supports every basic engine feature.

The Mandalorian: Ashes of the Empire

Jan 2021

• All class projects were made in 4 months. My role was to be the code leader and manage the 20-person team. My engine was used for the project and was upgraded by the code department and me, adding post-processing, shadow mapping and more features.

SKILLS & OTHER

Skills: C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, Python, Flutter, GLSL, Unity, Unreal Engine, GitHub, Git, Maya, Firebase, Jira, OpenGL, Tkinter, SDL, HTML, CSS, MonoRuntime.

Languages: Native in Spanish; Native in Catalan; C1 certified in English. **Volunteering:** Volunteered as event assistant at Canòdrom for a week (2021).